It's another enrollment period for our
fun way English and culture so for you
intermediate to advanced English
learners who want to improve your
English in the most effective and the
most interesting way possible you can
join now but there are limited places
and there's only a limited period of
time that you can sign up so if you
enjoy today's video head to
suzyyou.com/culture
to check it out so boys and girls what
are we learning about today we're going
to talk about relationships and dating
this lesson has been taught at Suzy but
it is not in our full annual curriculum
into British life and culture where
we've condensed and optimized our best
learning materials into a year of
learning for you but I thought it would
still give you a nice insight into the
kinds of things that we do so
relationships and dating part one we
have an alternating rotor of the types
of homeworks sometimes it's speaking so
you need to do some research and prepare
something to say in class for just a few
minutes sometimes it's reading
comprehension but what we will always
have is a video homework at the start of
each class to get the discussion going
so in this case we would start the
lesson with you either discussing a
famous British building car or fashion
brand so that would relate to last
week's topic or you could focus on a
particular design or designer from your
own country or we're pretty flexible you
can talk about anything that you want
it's a chance for you to speak and get
feedback from qualified teachers on your
speaking so I'm going to skip over the
video homework because for copyright
reasons I can't show you the video in
this video so let's just go through that
but what I do want to share with you is
the meaning of the ick to get the ick
this is a very specific phrase that
people are using at the moment for
dating it's like they start to get to
know someone and they think oh this
person seems quite nice quite
interesting maybe I like them and then
for some reason something changes
something happens where you suddenly
think oh no I don't like this person and
it can be the stupidest silliest thing
like maybe they have a Velcro wallet or
they slurp when they drink through a
straw it can be honestly the most
mundane of things and that's kind of the
joke with the ick is that it doesn't
have to be a real reason not to like
someone. You can just not like someone
for whatever reason at all. It just
describes that moment when you suddenly
think, "Ew, no. I don't like this
person." That is the ick. All right, so
lesson objectives for today are to learn
about relationships and dating culture
in the UK. Try your hand at being an
agony aunt. We'll find out what that
means and as always learn more useful
everyday phrases and vocabulary. Every
week there are 15 of these that we've
specifically chosen because they're so
useful and so commonly used, especially
in the UK. So you come away from each
lesson with concrete words and phrases
that you can start to use in your
speaking. Now this lesson starts with a
bit of a discussion. How would you
describe the dating scene in your
country? So the dating scene is like how
people date. Is it relaxed? Is it quite
strict? Maybe if you're from India for
example, there might be specific
arrangements. Maybe your family needs to
attend the dates or maybe it's totally
carefree and you can do whatever you
want. Do you think it's the same or
different to dating culture in the UK?
So we'll be talking about that in this
lesson and the last question for
everyone to discuss in their small
groups of three with the teacher is, do
you watch any dating shows? What's your
favorite one? And we will come to this
shortly. Here we have four words at the
bottom and we need to fill the blanks.
We have outright, spontaneously, banter,
and cheesy. Now you may not know what
these words mean. Let's talk about them.
Neither men nor women stop each other on
the street, declare their love from
across the road, something ask someone
out. So ask someone out is highlighted
as one of the key phrases for us to
learn this week. To ask someone out
means to ask them on a date. For
example, "Hey, would you like to get
coffee with me sometime?" Meaning I want
to date you. So because this starts with
the verb ask, before that verb, we
probably need something like an adverb.
If you remember, adverbs end with Y
usually or LY. So, it could be maybe
cheesy or spontaneously. Now,
spontaneously is like judong, like
proactively going over and asking
someone. You just have that feeling of
oh, yeah, I'm going to do this. I'm not
thinking about it too much. I'm just
going to ask that girl out. So, this
sentence is saying that in the UK, both
men and women do not do this. We are not
very spontaneous in our dating. So,
anyway, the missing word is
spontaneously. In Paris, love is
practiced as a sport at any given
moment. So, it's a bit of a joke saying
that in France, people are romantic all
the time. But, over in Britain, all that
seems something, if not problematic.
Even eye contact is risky. Here, if not
problematic means if it's not this first
adjective, then it's definitely the
second. If not something, if not
problematic means that it could even
seem problematic. So, the missing word
is cheesy. Cheesy means like cringey,
like ganga or loma, like overly romantic
with that cringey over-the-top feeling,
like oh, tag with a friend la. It's like
too much, too romantic. That's cheesy,
nothing to do with actual cheese. So, in
Britain, being very romantic can be seen
as cheesy and even more than that, it
could be seen as problematic, like it is
a problem. And the last bit is an
exaggeration, even eye contact is risky.
It's saying we are so avoidant of
romance that we don't even like to look
each other in the eye. Obviously, that's
not really true, that's just an
exaggeration, like a little joke. In the
UK, I sometimes leave a date thinking he
doesn't like me, but it turns out that
he does. British men won't tell you
their feelings.
What? We have outright or banter. We
could also use the word spontaneously
here, that would also be fine. Or, we
could also say British men won't tell
you their feelings outright. Outright
here means directly, like confess here
they go by.
So what do they do? Instead, sarcasm and
banter. So what is banter? It's like
playful teasing, like making fun of the
other person.
Like little jokes, like taking a dig or
a poke at you, making fun of you in a
light-hearted, fun way. So it's supposed
to be funny. And this type of humor is
often seen as flirting. And flirting is
that behavior that you do when you like
someone.
When there's that chemistry and vibe
between two people who maybe like each
other, and then there's flirting. Next
page here, we have three words: chat,
move, and date. After an online
discussion that feels more like a
something with a coworker, we could say
like a chat with a coworker, you finally
agree to meet for a drink. Never ever
call it a date. Again, this is a bit of
a joke. It shows how avoidant British
people are. It might clearly be a sign
of interest in the other person to go
for a drink with them after chatting,
but we would not say it's a date because
we're afraid of that word. It feels too
serious. People want to pretend like,
"No, no, no, it's just casual." Almost
like, "We're just friends." So then if
it goes badly, you can't say, "Oh, the
date went badly." It's more like, "Oh,
you know, I just had a chat with someone
and I'm not going to see them again, but
I didn't like them anyway." So we're
very shy and embarrassed to let others
know our feelings, which is why you
might not often hear people say that
it's a date. They don't want to reveal
that they actually like the other
person. I know it's a bit stupid, and
not everyone is like this. Alcohol is
ordered the very second you meet. That
means like that
at that moment. You meet and then bam,
alcohol in the largest volumes
available. Again, exaggeration, kind of
a joke, and consumed as fast as
possible. So, you get the idea. Brits
meet, they're like, "Oh, awkward. Need
to drink a lot of alcohol immediately."
But, nobody ever makes a
move. So, what is to make a move, and
why does nobody ever make a move in the
UK, no matter how drunk you are? Making
a move is like going to the next level.
So, maybe like touching the other
person, or saying, "I like you," or
maybe kissing them, or something that
shows actual affection, and like you
actually like them. Again, this is just
emphasizing the fact that British people
can be quite shy and awkward, and
avoidant of showing their feelings. So,
we're starting to get an idea of what
dating is really like in the UK. And if
we were in a real class, I might ask
you, is being sarcastic or teasing
someone seen as flirting in your
country? Are people awkward about the
terms they use, like the word date? And
would someone ask someone else out on
the street? Are people bold and brave
like that in your country? Obviously,
I've been mostly thinking of the US. On
American TV anyway, they seem very
confident and okay with asking someone
out, like, "Hey, want to go for a drink
sometime?" That would pretty much never
happen in the UK. It's all much more
quiet, secretive, underhand, and
confusing. Now, let's learn some useful
slang related to dating. Which of these
phrases mean either to end a
relationship, or to kiss someone
passionately? So, to end a relationship,
we have some words on the right here. To
break up with, to make out with, to get
off with, to split up with, to neck on,
to call it quits, to snog, and to dump
or be dumped by someone. As you can see,
most of them are phrasal verbs. Phrasal
verbs are incredibly common in English,
but they can be difficult to use, which
is why we need lots of practice. So,
which ones mean to end a relationship?
We've got to break up with. That's a fun
show, to break up with. He broke up with
me, and I don't know why. Now, to make
out with, that one means to kiss someone
passionately, but it's especially
American slang this one. Oh my god, I
saw you guys making out at school. That
was so gross. So, what would we say in
the UK instead? We would say get off
with. This is very slangy and something
teenagers would be more likely to say.
Like, oh yeah, got off with that girl
last night. She's well fit, mate. How
about to split up with? Do you think
that means kissing or breaking up? Well,
split is like funghi, so that is
breaking up. You could say that the
celebrity couple split up. That means
they ended their relationship. Now, neck
on is another way of saying kiss
passionately, especially in the north.
Like, they were necking on means they
were kissing a lot. Then we have to call
it quits. That means end a relationship
and it can also mean end other things
like, this game is not going very well.
Shall we just call it quits? Like, just
finish. Now, to snog, snog is a funny
one. It also means kiss passionately. It
brings to mind that image of two people
like,
you know, just like really going for it
with the kissing. Like, too much and
like a bit gross and maybe saliva and
stuff like that. So, that's snogging.
And then to dump or be dumped by. So,
you might know that to dump is like to
get rid of something. In the US, they
say the word dumpster, which is like the
rubbish bin where you put your rubbish
or trash as they say in the US. So, in
this case, it is to break up. Like, he
dumped me or I was dumped by him. Again,
it's quite casual slang, so you won't
see this in formal newspapers like The
Guardian or The Times. You're more
likely to see it in tabloid newspapers
like The Sun or The Mirror. Ooh, okay,
now we're talking about dating shows.
Have you seen these? Married at First
Sight and Naked Attraction. Let me tell
you what happens in these shows. Single
people take part in a social experiment
where they are matched with total
strangers by psychologists and dating
experts. So, they don't know the person
in advance and they're just matched
together. They meet for the very first
time on their wedding day, and then have
6 weeks to decide whether to make a go
of the marriage or separate. So, make a
go of here means to try it out, try the
marriage, see how it goes. And you could
also say make a go of the marriage or
dump each other, or call it quits, or
split up. All means the same thing. So,
how would you feel if you met someone
for the first day on your wedding day?
Like, it's an arranged marriage, you
meet them, boom, you're married. Would
that be uncomfortable? So, in this show,
obviously, it is quite uncomfortable
when they see each other, and they might
be like, "Oh, I am not attracted to this
person at all, but now we are married.
Yay." Question, would you trust a
psychologist or dating expert to match
you with a partner? If you are dating,
it could be quite helpful to have
someone say, "Hey, on paper, it seems
like your personality and stuff is going
to match with this other person." Maybe
it increases the odds that you will like
that person, or maybe these things are
very hard to predict. Like, on paper, it
looks like you guys should get on, but
actually you meet each other, and it's
like, "No, there's not a vibe here."
Now, what is the show Naked Attraction?
This is a very interesting one, worth a
watch if you're curious. Basically, a
clothed single person, so someone
wearing clothes, is presented with a
gallery of six naked potential partners.
So, literally, someone looking for a
partner stands there in clothes and
looks around at naked bodies, just the
bodies, and they can't see the face.
They are hidden behind booths, so
they're sort of in a like a box or
something. Their bodies and faces are
gradually revealed in different rounds
from the feet up. So, they start off by
just seeing the naked feet, and then
they see the naked legs, and then the
bum, and all of it, like all the
genitals, so it is quite a shocking
show. And then they go up and finally
see the face last. At each round, the
chooser eliminates one naked person
until only two are left. So, like
incredibly rude and harsh, right? It's
like, "Ooh, don't like your bum. See
you." What a weird idea for a show,
right? The chooser then takes their
clothes off to make the final choice.
So, they also don't get away with being
clothed the whole time. They do have to
take off their clothes eventually. So,
you end up with two naked people
standing there together and they are
like, "Now boyfriend and girlfriend or
something." Very strange, very strange.
So, are you surprised that this is shown
on British TV? You might think that
should be X-rated, like banned. Is it
not like pornographic? Well, it's
obviously not porn, it's just nudity.
But, it's still I guess quite
inappropriate and shocking to see on TV.
Here are some reviews about the show.
This show is so body positive. That
means it really celebrates people's
bodies. I love that they have regular
people instead of supermodel
bodybuilders. The contestants are young
and old, fat and thin, fit and flabby.
Flabby is like when you have fat that
kind of wiggles. It just goes to show
that looks aren't everything. And
everyone can be beautiful if they have a
positive attitude and are confident.
It's great to see people approach nudity
so casually and to discuss our bodies so
frankly and honestly. So, why does this
guy like the show? Well, he likes that
it's realistic. It's not just models and
perfect people. It's like all sorts of
different bodies that, you know, you got
big ones, small ones, fat ones, thin
ones. Everyone is welcome and they're
not openly critical about bodies. They
just try and make it light-hearted and
fun and everyone is welcome, basically.
That's why he likes the show. Now, how
about this other person, Ross, who gave
it one star? "I'm no prude." A prude
means someone who's very shy about
anything to do with like sexual or
bodily things. If they say, "I am no
prude," it means "I am not a prude."
But, this program removes the mystery
and the old-fashioned romance to meeting
a person for the first time. It's almost
like a cattle market. So, all the cows
lined up in a row and you need to choose
which one you want to eat. My
86-year-old mother-in-law also watched
it, shocked and appalled. That's a
different way of saying shocked in a bad
way. That young people would be
encouraged to go to such lengths on a TV
show, probably to get the ratings. So,
to go to lengths means to make the
effort and to do something more than you
usually would. We both agree that this
is one program to miss in the future.
So, they really did not like it. They
didn't like the fact that people were
like parading their bodies around to try
and get approval from others. So, who do
you agree with more? What do you think?
And this was a news headline. It says,
"A new low, explicit UK show Naked
Attraction causes a stir in the US." So,
what does this mean? Well, a new low
means the worst point or lowest level
ever reached in a behavior or situation.
It's like there was bad and then there's
really bad. That's a new low. And you
can use this in speaking, like, "Oh, I
missed the train yesterday, but today I
missed a flight. That's a new low." And
then the adjective explicit means
containing very clear or detailed
content. It's like too much detail, you
can see everything kind of thing. More
detail than you want to see, especially
like nudity. Or you might have a song
that says it's explicit, maybe they use
a lot of swear words and graphic
language to do with sex usually. And
what does to cause a stir mean? That
means to cause excitement, controversy,
or widespread attention. So, like people
talking, people being shocked, like a
big reaction. That's a stir. So, are you
surprised that American audiences are
seen as more prudish than British ones?
So, we've got that word prude again. So,
it's like being shy or awkward or
embarrassed about bodily or sexual
things. Maybe if we think of
stereotypes, we think of Americans as
being more bold and outgoing, maybe they
would be more comfortable with a show
like this. But actually, the headline is
saying that they did not appreciate this
show in the US. And do you have any sort
of show like this in your country? I
would be very surprised if you do, to be
honest. So, there's more to talk about
here. Agony aunts. Agony aunts is when
you write a letter into the newspaper
and someone, usually an older lady who
works at the newspaper, she'll reply and
give you advice on your dating
situation. So, it's very interesting,
but I'm running out of time today, so I
don't think I can finish this lesson
now. As you can see, there's lots more
interesting content. If you like this
sort of thing, if you want to get stuck
into British culture and improve your
English that way, then I highly, highly
recommend joining our Trem Fang Wei in
Yu Wen Hua Ke Tang. It's all this sort
of stuff about different every week. You
can check out the curriculum online at
susiebu.com/culture.
As I said, now is the time that you can
enroll, but it's a limited time and
there are limited spaces. That's because
we have a very select few teachers who
have been carefully chosen by me for
their excellent chat and teaching
abilities and qualifications. So, it's
great fun. I hope you can join us. It's
really practical. It's going to get you
speaking English much better and also
give you a broad awareness of the
culture behind the language, which for
me is the most interesting part. So,
that's all for today. Thanks for
watching. I'm Susie. See you next time.
Oh, and by the way, if there's a
specific topic that you would love to
know about, maybe on this YouTube
channel or maybe we can add it to our
culture course, do let us know. You can
drop us an email or you can drop a
comment below this video. We'd love to
know what you guys find interesting. All
right, see you.